[
  {
    "question": "Where is the Great Wall of China?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["Asia", "Africa", "Europe", "America"],
    "answer": ["Asia"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35b9e5a79fb1b731aa7f5"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long did it take to build and finish the Great Wall of China?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["2 years", "20 years", "200 years", "2000 years"],
    "answer": ["2000 years"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35b9e5a79fb1b731aa7f5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did they build the Great Wall of China?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "to make China more beautiful",
      "to protect China from enemies",
      "to be in World Record",
      "to make Chinese people exercise more"
    ],
    "answer": ["to protect China from enemies"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35b9e5a79fb1b731aa7f5"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is length of the Great Wall of China?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "about 2100 meters",
      "about 21,000 meters",
      "about 2100 kilometers",
      "about 21,000 kilometers"
    ],
    "answer": ["about 21,000 kilometers"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35b9e5a79fb1b731aa7f5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Great Wall of China is located in ...",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "the North of China",
      "the South of China",
      "the West of China",
      "the East of China"
    ],
    "answer": ["the North of China"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35b9e5a79fb1b731aa7f5"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long does it take to walk the Great Wall for the full length?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "at least 5 months",
      "at least 10 months",
      "at least 17 months",
      "at least 2 years"
    ],
    "answer": ["at least 17 months"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35b9e5a79fb1b731aa7f5"
  },
  {
    "question": "What were the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      " Monuments built in Asia. Some of the cities include Thailand, Hong Kong, and Singapore.",
      "Monuments built in Egypt, Rome, and Thailand.",
      "Monuments built in Europe, Africa, and Western Asia.",
      "Monuments built in the U.S."
    ],
    "answer": ["Monuments built in Europe, Africa, and Western Asia."],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35ea1d9bf4e3d8c0c976e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the Great Pyramid of Giza built?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["Turkey.", "Giza.", "Europe.", "Egypt."],
    "answer": ["Egypt."],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35ea1d9bf4e3d8c0c976e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Taj Mahal is a tomb for",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["soldiers", "a king's wife", "rich people", "the poor"],
    "answer": ["a king's wife"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35ea1d9bf4e3d8c0c976e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Eiffel Tower opened in 1880 for",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "the World's Fair",
      "the end of the French Revolution",
      "the Olympic games",
      "the celebration of Paris' 100th birthday"
    ],
    "answer": ["the World's Fair"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35ea1d9bf4e3d8c0c976e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Stonehenge is located in",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["England", "Ireland", "France", "Spain"],
    "answer": ["England"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35ea1d9bf4e3d8c0c976e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was the Great Wall of China bulit?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "As a means of defense",
      "To be a tourist attraction",
      "To use up leftover bricks",
      "All of these answers."
    ],
    "answer": ["As a means of defense"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35ea1d9bf4e3d8c0c976e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Chichen Itza used for?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "hosting dances and celebrations",
      "religious ceremonies",
      "performing medical procedures",
      "growing food"
    ],
    "answer": ["religious ceremonies"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35ea1d9bf4e3d8c0c976e"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the oldest structure on the ancient list of the seven wonders?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "The Great Pyramids of Giza",
      "Lighthouse of Alexandria",
      "Great Wall of China",
      "Statue of Zeus at Olympia"
    ],
    "answer": ["The Great Pyramids of Giza"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a35ea1d9bf4e3d8c0c976e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some medicines are only available on ................",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["description", "instruction", "inscription", "prescription"],
    "answer": ["prescription"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3625da73cdb7257ef7913"
  },
  {
    "question": "It's difficult to ................... the difference between margarine and butter.",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["speak", "tell", "say", "look"],
    "answer": ["tell"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3625da73cdb7257ef7913"
  },
  {
    "question": "A .................. is a printed pamphlet about a place, product, or company that is used for advertising.",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["media", "visa", "passport", "brochure"],
    "answer": ["brochure"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3625da73cdb7257ef7913"
  },
  {
    "question": "You can’t leave Phu Quoc ................. tasting 'bun quay'.",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["without", "with", "in", "to"],
    "answer": ["without"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3625da73cdb7257ef7913"
  },
  {
    "question": "The beginning of Mekong River is ..............",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "Tibetan Plateau, China",
      "Beijing, China",
      "Ningxia, China",
      "Xinjiang, China"
    ],
    "answer": ["Tibetan Plateau, China"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3625da73cdb7257ef7913"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the other name of Mekong River basin in Vietnam?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["Red River", "Tien River", "Nine-Dragon River", "Cai Be River"],
    "answer": ["Nine-Dragon River"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3625da73cdb7257ef7913"
  },
  {
    "question": "Since we live by an airport, we can easily watch the airplanes ……… off",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["take", "to take", "be taking", "will take"],
    "answer": ["take"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3625da73cdb7257ef7913"
  },
  {
    "question": "I seldom forget ……… my teeth before going to bed",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["brush", "to brush", "brushing", "brushed"],
    "answer": ["to brush"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3625da73cdb7257ef7913"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the Spanish Armada defeated?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["1688", "1588", "1701", "1401"],
    "answer": ["1588"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36583031fa2a33bc38d5d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Ethiopian emperor who defeated an invading Italian army?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["Menelik II", "Taytu Betul", "Oreste Baratieri", "Aaron Burr"],
    "answer": ["Menelik II"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36583031fa2a33bc38d5d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which general's mistake caused the Zhao to lose the battle of Changping?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["Bao Qi", "Lian Po", "Zhao She", "Zhao Kuo"],
    "answer": ["Zhao Kuo"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36583031fa2a33bc38d5d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which former vice president plotted against the US government in the 1800s?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "Richard Nixon",
      "Aaron Burr",
      "Harry Truman",
      "George H.W. Bush"
    ],
    "answer": ["Aaron Burr"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36583031fa2a33bc38d5d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where were hundreds of Native Americans massacred by U.S. troops in 1890?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "Lakota Reservation Hill",
      "Little Big Horn",
      "Sitting Bull River",
      "Wounded Knee Creek"
    ],
    "answer": ["Wounded Knee Creek"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36583031fa2a33bc38d5d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two military defeats were caused by both an opposing army/navy and the weather?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "The defeat of the Spanish Armada",
      "The Italian defeat in Ethiopia",
      "The charge of the Light Brigade",
      "Napoleon's defeat in Russia"
    ],
    "answer": ["The defeat of the Spanish Armada"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36583031fa2a33bc38d5d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which car sometimes exploded after even a slight impact?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["Ford Pinto", "Tesla", "Ford Explorer", "Toyota Corolla"],
    "answer": ["Ford Pinto"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36583031fa2a33bc38d5d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do the roles of men and women differ in your family?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "Most of men don’t want to stay at home.",
      "Women are changing their roles.",
      "Most men are very bossy and arrogant.",
      "Men are breadwinners and women are caregivers."
    ],
    "answer": ["Men are breadwinners and women are caregivers."],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36a259a37ae6720ac85a8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gender discrimination must ____ in order to create a better society.",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["be extended", "be eliminated", "eliminating", "extend"],
    "answer": ["be eliminated"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36a259a37ae6720ac85a8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Domestic violence ____ women and girls must be wiped out at any cost. a better society.",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["on", "at", "against", "for"],
    "answer": ["against"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36a259a37ae6720ac85a8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gender discrimination should _______ eliminated so that everyone has equal opportunities in education.",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["have", "been", "be", "have be"],
    "answer": ["be"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36a259a37ae6720ac85a8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which diagram can show us the AMOUNT OF ENERGY that flows from producers to consumers?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["Food chain", "Food web", "Food pyramid"],
    "answer": ["Food pyramid"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36ddd7b25295743ed5ac3"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will happen to a population if they do not have enough resources?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "The population will grow bigger",
      "The population will all die",
      "The population will have to move away or they will die",
      "The population will sit and wait for new resources"
    ],
    "answer": ["The population will have to move away or they will die"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36ddd7b25295743ed5ac3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is a HARMFUL change that plants can make to their ecosystem?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "They put oxygen in the atmosphere.",
      "They can grow over other plants and steal their space and nutrients.",
      "Their roots keep the ground stable and prevents erosion.",
      "They provide shelter for many animals."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "They can grow over other plants and steal their space and nutrients."
    ],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36ddd7b25295743ed5ac3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Humans change their ecosystem all the time. Most of these changes are harmful. How can we stop harming our environment?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "Continue to use fossil fuels for cars and vehicles.",
      "Make more green spaces in cities with lots of plants.",
      "Wear masks when we go outside.",
      "Continue to develop and build bigger cities."
    ],
    "answer": ["Make more green spaces in cities with lots of plants."],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36ddd7b25295743ed5ac3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some animals change their environment by burrowing in the ground. This means they make tunnels in the ground. How can this be a HELPFUL change?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "They can destroy the roots of plants.",
      "They put air in the ground that makes it easy for water to flow through.",
      "They can cause erosion- the ground moves away.",
      "They destroy habitats of other animals that live in the ground."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "They put air in the ground that makes it easy for water to flow through."
    ],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36ddd7b25295743ed5ac3"
  },
  {
    "question": "When does COMPETITION happen in an ecosystem?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "When there is enough resources for all living things to survive.",
      "When animals move away from their ecosystem.",
      "When two or more living things need the same resource to survive."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "When two or more living things need the same resource to survive."
    ],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a36ddd7b25295743ed5ac3"
  },
  {
    "question": "_______ is the process of taking oxygen into the body and releasing carbon dioxide back into the environment.",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "cellular respiration",
      "breathing",
      "diffusion",
      "respiratory system"
    ],
    "answer": ["breathing"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a370c0d34eabf98b7403f2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do animals need oxygen?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "To get food for their bodies",
      "To burn food for energy",
      "To get rid of carbon dioxide",
      "To protect themselves from predators"
    ],
    "answer": ["To burn food for energy"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a370c0d34eabf98b7403f2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which shows the correct path oxygen flows through our body?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "mouth → blood → cells → lungs",
      "mouth → lungs → blood → cells",
      "cells → blood → lungs → mouth",
      "blood → cells → mouth → lungs"
    ],
    "answer": ["mouth → lungs → blood → cells"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a370c0d34eabf98b7403f2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is NOT a respiratory structure found in animals?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["Lungs", "Gills", "Skin", "Fur"],
    "answer": ["Fur"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a370c0d34eabf98b7403f2"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do axolotls obtain oxygen?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "Their gills absorb it from the water.",
      "They take it in when they breathe the air.",
      "Their eyes absorb it from the water.",
      "Axolotls do not need oxygen."
    ],
    "answer": ["Their gills absorb it from the water."],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a370c0d34eabf98b7403f2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Galaxies are composed of (best answer)",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "stars",
      "stars and gas",
      "stars, dust, and gas",
      "stars, dust, and gas held together by gravity"
    ],
    "answer": ["stars, dust, and gas held together by gravity"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3729964024979268a18d6"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Milky Way Galaxy is a _____________ galaxy.",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["spiral", "lenticular", "elliptical", "irregular"],
    "answer": ["spiral"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3729964024979268a18d6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is not a type of galaxy?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": [
      "Optical Galaxy",
      "Spiral Galaxy",
      "Elliptical Galaxy",
      "Irregular Galaxy"
    ],
    "answer": ["Optical Galaxy"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3729964024979268a18d6"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many stars are in a galaxy?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["millions or billions", "thousands", "hundreds", "Ten"],
    "answer": ["millions or billions"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3729964024979268a18d6"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many stars are there in our galaxy?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["200", "200,000", "200 million", "200 billion"],
    "answer": ["200 billion"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3729964024979268a18d6"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many exoplanets have been found around other stars?",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["none", "5,000", "18", "1,789"],
    "answer": ["5,000"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3729964024979268a18d6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Stars that have two stars in one solar system are called ____________ stars.",
    "type": "multiple_choice",
    "options": ["binary", "tertiary", "quaternary", "hybrid"],
    "answer": ["binary"],
    "timer": 30,
    "set": "62a3729964024979268a18d6"
  }
]
